In the last video,
في الفيديو الأخير،
we got an idea of what the standard deviation is measuring.
حصلنا على فكرة حول قياس الانحراف المعياري.
In this video, we will look at
وفي هذا الفيديو، سنلقي نظرة على
the math that actually occurs when calculating this measure.
العملية الحسابية التي تحدث بالفعل عند حساب هذا الإجراء.
We will work with data to calculate this measure as well as associate notation with it.
سنعمل مع البيانات لحساب هذا الإجراء بالإضافة إلى ربطه به.
It is worth noting that after this lesson,
تجدر الإشارة إلى أنه بعد هذا الدرس،
you probably won't calculate this measure by hand ever again,
ربما لن تقوم بحساب هذا القياس يدويًا مرة أخرى،
because you'll learn software to do it for you.
لأنك ستعرف برنامجًا يقوم به نيابة عنك.
The calculating it yourself will give you intuition behind what it's actually doing.
سيعطيك حسابه بنفسك الحدس وراء ما يفعله البرنامج بالفعل.
And this intuition is necessary to become good at
وهذا الحدس ضروري لكي تصبح جيدًا في
understanding data and choosing the right analysis for your situation.
فهم البيانات واختيار التحليل الصحيح لحالتك.
Imagine we have a data set with four values,
تخيل أن لدينا مجموعة بيانات تحتوي على أربع قيم،
10, 14, 10, and 6.
10 و 14 و 10 و 6.
The first thing we need to do to calculate the standard deviation is to find the mean.
أول شيء يتعين علينا القيام به لحساب الانحراف المعياري هو إيجاد المتوسط.
In notation, we have this as X bar.
وحسب الترقيم، لدينا هذا باعتباره شريط X.
For our values, the sum is 40,
بالنسبة لقيمنا، يكون المجموع 40،
and we have four numbers.
ولدينا أربعة أرقام.
So the mean is 40 over 4 or 10.
إذن المتوسط يكون 40 فوق 4 أو 10.
Then we want to look at the distance of each observation from this mean.
ثم نريد إلقاء نظرة على مسافة كل ملاحظة من هذا المتوسط.
Two of these observations are exactly equal to the mean.
اثنين من هذه الملاحظات تساوي بالضبط المتوسط.
So the distance here is zero.
إذن المسافة هنا هي صفر.
One is 4 larger the 14,
حيث إن أحد الأعداد أكبر بنسبة 4، وهو 14،
while the other is 4 smaller the 6.
في حين أن الآخر أصغر بنسبة 4، وهو 6.
In notation, each of these is XI minus X bar.
وحسب الترقيم، كل من هذين يكون XI ناقص X شريط.
Then, if we were to average these distances,
ثم، إذا اردنا حساب متوسط​هذه المسافات،
the positive would cancel with the negative value.
فسيتم إلغاء القيمة الإيجابية بالقيمة السالبة.
And the value of zero isn't a great measure of the spread here.
وقيمة الصفر ليست مقياس انتشار كبيرا هنا.
Zero would suggest that all the values are the same or that there's no spread.
حيث يشير الصفر إلى أن جميع القيم هي نفسها أو أنه لا يوجد فرق.
So instead, we need to make all of these values positive.
لذا بدلاً من ذلك، نحتاج إلى جعل كل هذه القيم إيجابية.
The way we do this when calculating the standard deviation is by squaring them all.
الطريقة التي نقوم بها عند حساب الانحراف المعياري هي عن طريق تربيعها كلها.
If we do that here,
إذا فعلنا ذلك هنا،
our negative and positive 4 values will become 16s.
فستصبح قيمنا الأربعة السلبية والإيجابية 16 قيمة.
Now, we could average these to find the average
الآن، يمكننا أن نجد متوسط هذه القيم لإيجاد متوسط
squared distance of each observation from the mean.
المسافة التربيعية لكل ملاحظة من المتوسط.
This is called the variance.
وهذا ما يسمى الفرق.
Finding the average, just as we did before,
إيجاد المتوسط بنفس الطريقة التي فعلناها سابقًا،
means adding all of these values and dividing by how many there are.
يعني إضافة جميع هذه القيم وقسمتها على عددها.
In our case, we had 0, 16,
في حالتنا، كان لدينا 0، 16،
0, 16 and we divide by 4 because we have four observations.
0، 16 ونقسمها على 4 لأن لدينا أربع ملاحظات.
However, this is an average of
ومع ذلك، فإن هذا هو متوسط
squared values which we only did to get positive values in the first place.
القيم التربيعية التي قمنا بها فقط للحصول على قيم إيجابية في المقام الأول.
So to get our standard deviation,
حتى نحصل على الانحراف المعياري،
we take the square root of this ending value.
نأخذ الجذر التربيعي لهذه القيمة النهائية.
Here, our standard deviation is 2.83.
هنا، يكون الانحراف المعياري 2.83.
So this is on average how far each point in our data set is from the mean,
إذن، هذا متوسط المسافة التي تبعدها كل نقطة في مجموعة بياناتنا من المتوسط،
which is the definition of the standard deviation.
وهو تعريف الانحراف المعياري.